# Luke Wickens Software Developer

☑ lukewickens1989@gmail.com

**\** 07368481653

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/lukewickens/

https://github.com/lukewickens1989/



After working in the finance industry for five years, I am looking for a new challenge and am in the process of completing the Makers Academy bootcamp.

I have had a passion for software development from a young age and coupled with my interest in finance and cryptocurrency, I am looking to make the move into the Blockchain space.

#### **TECH STACK**

Back End, Solidity, Web3.js, Node.js, Rails, Sinatra, SQL (PostgreSQL)

Front End, JavaScript/React.js, Ruby

**Testing,** Mocha/Chai, Jasmine, RSpec, Capybara

**Other,** Git/GitHub/GitLabs, MetaMask, Truffle Suite (Ganache), Remix, TravisCI, CodeClimate (CD), Heroku/Surge

#### **SKILLS**

Proactive problem-solving Time management

Team player Self-driven

Excellent written and communication skills Accountable

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Blockchain Developer, Extropy.io

March 2021 – present

- Smart contract design and development in Solidity.
- Using OpenZeppelin for contract standardisation.
- Smart contract testing with Remix.
- DApp development and testing using Truffle.
- Utilising Ganache/Metamask for testing contracts.
- Web3.js
- Writing smart contract wrappers for front end integration.
- JavaScript/React.js front end development.
- Researching new technology, such as L2 solutions for contract gas optimisation.
- Debugging smart contracts.

#### **Trainee Software Developer,** *Makers Academy*

• A full stack coding bootcamp which teaches an industry-led, language agnostic curriculum.

- Heavy focus on TDD, utilised version control, CI/CD and pair programming.
- Daily use of Agile methodologies through daily stand ups, weekly retrospectives, code reviews and project management through Trello.
- Building own testing framework for use with a note taking app.
- Dedicated emotional intelligence curriculum.

November 2020 – February 2021

### Fund Pricing Analyst, Marlborough Fund Managers Ltd

• Investigation and reconciliation of bank statements and fund information to ensure accurate and correct information between them.

March 2019 – November 2020

# Trainee Paraplanner, MGP Investment Management Ltd

- Producing annual and bi-annual valuation reports for clients and advisers (complete with performance assessment, income statements, and sector weighting graphs).
- Writing client reports based upon advisers' recommendations (both portfolio performance reports and recommendation reports).

December 2018 – March 2019

#### Company Director, BPDS & Sons Limited

- Proactively resourcing bespoke transport and logistic solutions to enhance the customer experience.
- Reviewing current practices to analyse possible implementations to increase efficiency.

February 2016 – October 2018

# **Senior Custody Transfers Administrator,** *Investec Wealth & Investment*

- Received and transferred over 1500 new client portfolios from other major brokers including, UBS, JP Morgan, Barclays, Merrill Lynch, and HSBC.
- Mentoring new members of the team and provide on the job training to existing members in line with company standards.

September 2012 – February 2016

# **PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATIONS**

**IOC (Chartered Institute of Securities and Investments)** (Level I - Introduction to Investment)

IOC (Chartered Institute of Securities and Investments) (Level II - Financial Regulations)

**IOC (Chartered Institute of Securities and Investments)** (Level III - Collective Investment Scheme Administration)

**DipFP (Chartered Insurance Institute)** (R01 - Financial Services, Regulation and Ethics)

# **EDUCATION**

(BA Hons) Business Management, Liverpool John Moores Univesity

2011

Business Management degree with an emphasis on Finance.

#### **AWARDS**

**Associate (ACSI),** Chartered Institute of Securities and Investments

2019

#### **INTERESTS**

# Pool and Open-water Swimming

Competitive club swimmer and 200m butterfly club record holder. Also competed in The Great North Swim on behalf of Macmillan Cancer Support and The Chill Swim.

### Reading

An avid reader of Sci-fi and Fantasy novels. My favourites include The Riftwar Saga by Raymond E. Feist and Lord of the Rings Trilogy by J.R.R. Tolkien

## Blogging 2

I have started to enjoy blogging about tech on my medium account.